<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Aaron's Blog</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Aaron's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronheld.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Embracing change</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/embracing-change/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/embracing-change/</guid><description>
&lt;p>It's a month past due so here is my obligatory &amp;quot;I changed my job&amp;quot; post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last nearly 8 years at Comcast as part of the 'Online' group and later as founding member of mighty &lt;a href="http://blog.comcast.com/comcast-interactive-media-cim/" title="CIM @ Voices">Comcast Interactive Media&lt;/a> I've made many business connections, met a number of excellent peers and forged a few relationships that will last a lifetime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a happily married 40+ dad with mortgage and college payments I often feel over the hill with regards to blogging and living out loud. As a Manager with a sometimes disproportional ego I also felt an obligation to 'disappear' for some time in order to give &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/tomjbarker">@tomjbarker&lt;/a> room to make the team his own. I've no doubt that he will take what we started to the next level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I joined Comcast we had acquired a portal using technology from the last millennium (JSP, coded like it was 1999). It was hosted by a company we competed with and after 3 months I gave up trying to get a stable build from the source code. We merged with a development team who hired java test writers because 'real' developers don't waste time writing unit tests. 2 key executives took this mess and in what I have to call a 'visionary' move decided to craft a 'web development' culture within Comcast. I'll always be indebted to Sam Schwartz for doing whatever he did to convince Comcast that splitting off a wholly owned subsidiary as a web shop would be a good idea. That gave us the opportunity and Charlie Herrin was the one whose personality and direction shaped our day to day work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The early days were exciting and we took an empty room and filled it with whirring servers powering a living architecture that grew up to power &lt;a href="http://xfinity.com">xfinity.com&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://xfinityTV.comcast.net">xfinityTV.comcast.net&lt;/a> (The architecture we used was this new thing called REST wrapping a key based XML document store). We took a team who didn't understand testing in an untestable environment to a group passionate around TDD.  We introduced Java/Oracle biased executives to the wonders of S3, Node and Rails. Code bases with 0 tests now have thousands of meaningful ones. We went from developers oncall 24/7 and my phone ringing 3 nights a week to me sitting in the park with my kids as the software absorbed feed failures and gracefully degraded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was the architect (along with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/kmartino">@kmartino&lt;/a>) and a primary coder of the software stack and trained a team to support it. That team has surpassed me in every way as coders.  The level of individual talent is staggering.  A CIM jr engineer would be a Sr at any other company in Philly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The business models of CIM were fairly mature and the products were very much in an incremental growth phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I got a call from a headhunter looking for someone to lead a development team for an Energy company.  I was skeptical because I didn't really get the new competitive energy market and didn't really trust the companies selling it.  When I met some of the marketing folk they hooked with me with a simple pitch.  Nobody really knows how to market energy and &lt;a href="http://www.energypluscompany.com">Energy Plus&lt;/a> is going to figure it out.  They have a business team that is incredibly agile and data driven with not an ego driven decision in sight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a new company they had much of their infrastructure built by waves of vendors who made a hash of their codebase.  They have made a real investment in IT to make us part of their competitive advantage and I'm looking forward to the challenges.  Right now companies build a plant and sell energy, in the future they will have to market it.  Much like Comcast formed CIM to figure out how to do web development, Energy Plus was acquired by NRG in order to figure out how to market energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are doing business iterations and retrospectives in order to invest in what works and adjust what is not optimal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing hammered how good they are  into my head as much as my first meeting with our finance team.  They were asking for development help for some statistics they were compiling.  I'd heard they were trying to use python to download some data and analyze it in excel.  I walked in thinking I'm the big python expert and with a passing knowledge of '&lt;a href="http://www.r-project.org/">R&lt;/a>' was going to be able to help them. They described the flow of downloading, parsing, processing, analyzing and explained it was a manual process done daily.  I asked how long it takes them thinking I'm about to save some poor human hours a day.  They said about 1omin since its all scripted.  They just have to run a batch file.  Wow, I know developers that don't take time to automate like this.  The downloading is solid python analyzing is hardcore R.  They are professional enough to come to me to 'operationalize' this as the next step.  There really are no 'B' players here and when someone on the business side asks me for 'help' it is for real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So in short the only thing keeping us from being fully agile is engineering, which means the only barrier to agile is ME getting it done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And for this story I have no blockers ;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crowdsourcing the arts and a misunderstood artist is seen in a new light</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/crowdsourcing-the-arts-and-a-misunderstood-artist-is-seen-in-a-new-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/crowdsourcing-the-arts-and-a-misunderstood-artist-is-seen-in-a-new-light/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This weekend I attended a &lt;a href="http://www.skny.com/" title="Sean Kelly Gallery">gallery&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.skny.com/exhibitions/2011-05-07_robert-mapplethorpe/" title="50 Americans">opening&lt;/a> of an exhibition called '50 Americans' featuring the work of &lt;a href="http://www.mapplethorpe.org/">Robert&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://artsy.net/artist/robert-mapplethorpe">Mapplethorpe&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually I have to spend the first few minutes or an Art exhibition reading the background to understand the story that the gallery is telling through the art.  This one was different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rather then view the Mapplethorpe images through the lens of an expert Sean Kelly's people found 50 Americans, one per state, to curate the selection.  They were nervous about what selections the wisdom of the crowd would choose to surface.  Some people involved with the Mapplethorpe foundation were initially skeptical of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proving once again trust and risk often yield success these 50 random Americans put together a selection of images that were stunning.  I was able to walk though the gallery, take in an image, and read a short selection about why that image was selected by an American.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Americans ranged through every cross section I could think of, from successful businessmen (Owner of local favorite &lt;a href="http://www.dogfish.com/">Dogfish&lt;/a>) to a Rabbi to my lovely wife.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/9vpmz.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/9vpmz-300x225.jpg" alt="" title="Ms Pa">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mapplethorpe is often remembered for the controversy surrounding his images.  They have been called exploitive, indecent or simply obscene.  Surprisingly all I saw was crisp compelling photos with an extraordinary use of light and contrast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Experts&amp;quot; in academia has praised his artistic works.  &amp;quot;Experts&amp;quot; in law and government have condemned his work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out average Americans just want the opportunity to enjoy his work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Mapplethorpe-330x278.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/Mapplethorpe-330x278-300x252.jpg" alt="" title="Mapplethorpe Flag">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>  See more of his work at &lt;a href="https://artsy.net/artist/robert-mapplethorpe">Artsy's Robert Mapplethorpe page&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feel bad for GM, I couldn't make this up</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/feel-bad-for-gm-i-couldnt-make-this-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/feel-bad-for-gm-i-couldnt-make-this-up/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I went researching to Chevy Volt to find some facts to offset my calculator below. I did get lots of feedback about people thinking that price is not the only factor here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when I went to chevy to look at 'affordability' I found this. Check the URL [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_229&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;441&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;GM Working on affordability&amp;quot;]&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/Picture-2.png" alt="GM Working on affordability" title="GM Working on affordability">[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ROI of MPG</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/roi-of-mpg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/roi-of-mpg/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I've been car shopping lately and thinking about what mileage I need in the new vehicle. The cars that I like and are more fun to drive hover just under 30mpg while the 35+ models tend to be a bit mushy on the gas (or tiny)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I came across this: &lt;a href="http://www.comcast.net/articles/finance/20090811/US.GM.Volt.Mileage/" title="Volt">http://www.comcast.net/articles/finance/20090811/US.GM.Volt.Mileage&lt;/a>/&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GM is unveiling a car that get 230MPG in the city!  I thought that was awesome until I came across 3 facts&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>That mileage is in City driving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The car is not shipping yet (and all my projects are 'bug free' until they ship also)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The car is $40k&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I wrote up a quick app to let me calculate how many miles I have to drive in order to recoup the $40k price tag.  Even comparing it against a $20k hybrid that gets 50 MPG I still have to drive almost 320,000 miles to break even! (at $4/gal)&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/mpg_roi.html" width="440px" height="470px">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>The Taking of Pelham 123</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/the-taking-of-pelham-123/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/the-taking-of-pelham-123/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Taking of Pelham 123 on Fancast!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went looking for the trailer of the original Pelham 123 and was plesantly surprised to find the full lenght movie on Fancast!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was one of my favorite movies as a kid and well worth watching. There are some comments out there about how this is a well done film in terms of pacing, so I hope that they model that in the remake.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="http://www.fancast.com/movies/The-Taking-of-Pelham-1%2C-2%2C-3/22089/828490151/The-Taking-of-Pelham-1%2C-2%2C-3-%3A-Full-Length/embed" width="420" height="355" scrolling="no" frameborder="0">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>I really enjoyed Taken</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/i-really-enjoyed-taken-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/i-really-enjoyed-taken-2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Just watched &lt;a href="http://www.fancast.com/movies/Taken/141653/full-movie">Taken&lt;/a> and it was a well done film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It had a pace more akin to the Bourne movies with a better actor at the helm. I don't know why it didn't do so well at the box office, I thought that it had more emotional impact then any recent spy type movies I've seen. The action sequences were more of a desperate warrior then a calm martial artist and every scene imparted tension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend watching it and I'm definitely sure that as a parent I'm never letting my kids travel alone......&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>good meal at table 31 in Philladelphia</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/good-meal-at-table-31-in-philladelphia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/good-meal-at-table-31-in-philladelphia/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We went to Table 31 at the base of the Comcast center for dinner tonight.  It was an excellent restaurant week menu.  Most of the places doing restaurant week push the up-sell pretty hard but this was an exception.  They had the all inclusive $35 menu on the table.  Even better they had a selection of wines under $50 that they recommended and our was very nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The waiter was very nice and handled my 'special needs' diet.  Well at least I think that he did, but I'll know for sure tomorrow if I accidentally ingested some wheat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mummers here and abroad</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/mummers-here-and-abroad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/mummers-here-and-abroad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Philadelphia: 1, England 0&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;180&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Philly mummers&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mummers_Parade">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/180px-3161.jpg" alt="Philly mummers" title="Philly Mummers">&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignleft&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;180&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;English Mummers&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mummers_Play">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/180px-Westonmummers.JPG" alt="English Mummers" title="English Mummers">&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Giving up on Apple (mouse)</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/giving-up-on-apple-mouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/giving-up-on-apple-mouse/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My girlfriend's mom bought her one of those inexpensive 'wireless' notebook mouses.  It is not even bluetooth enabled, it requires a USB adapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used it over the weekend and found it much better then my hip Apple mouse. Although I can't squeeze it ( &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/mightymouse/">www.apple.com/mightymouse/&lt;/a> ) it is much easier to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tilt wheel concept is more precise then the little ball on the apple and the optical sensor works across any surface. This mouse works on my office desk where the apple mouse fails (and a dog did eat my mousepad)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway consider this a product endorsement, and go get a Logitech v200. I'm off to find a bluetooth version....&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=aarhel-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=6&amp;amp;l=st1&amp;amp;mode=pc-hardware&amp;amp;search=v200%20mouse&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;lt1=&amp;amp;lc1=3366FF&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width="120" height="150" border="0" frameborder="0" style="border:none;" scrolling="no">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>BarCampPhilly part 2</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcampphilly-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcampphilly-part-2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.arpitonline.com">Arpit&lt;/a> led another session about how and when to use Flash in an Ajax world. One of the attendees was a Microsoft Silverlight manager and was a solid hour of dispelling myths about RIA in general. There is still a large population that thinks Flash/Silverlight are bad for SEO and not enough people know of Adobe's recent collaborations with Google and Microsoft, including project Ichabod that makes Flash more indexable than Ajax (some details here: &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/adobe">http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/adobe&lt;/a>_ichabod_flash_ajax.php). We also talked about how the RIA vs traditional html choice is often made unconsciously before the IA/Design phase and what we need to do in order to help inform that choice. Arpit is going to have a conversation later with a manager from Microsoft concerning Rich Internet Application development in Philadelphia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin Fitzpatrick led an afternoon session about &amp;quot;Getting your Ideas Out&amp;quot; that was standing room only by the time the session began. Kevin's premise was simple: You have more to worry from your idea never seeing the light of day than from it being stolen and used by someone else. He encouraged the attendees to put their ideas out as soon as they could and leverage the community to shape it to its final form. While the session was limited to an hour, the excitement in the room could have easily kept the discussion going for hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most interesting part of the event was the repeated references to Frank Eliason and the comcastcares twitter account. In a more that a couple of talks, comcastcares was used as an example on how big companies are now &amp;quot;getting it&amp;quot;, on how Frank's help to one of the attendees has now made her a loyal comcast customer as well as one discussion on how someone on Verizon FIOS was annoyed that they did not have a verizoncares twitter account. One of the attendees then pinged Frank on Twitter and he actually dropped in in person (though none of the CIM team managed to meet him since all this happened with no CIM member around). comcastcares was the biggest discussion topic on the ROI on Social Media talk as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other sessions we attended included how to get your organization to embrace web standards by Kimberly Blessing, a former AOL employee that led the first standards-compliant redesign of AOL.com back in 2004. Standards are a hot topic as we look for ways to reduce our engineering footprint and reuse our systems better. Standards lead the way for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our future plans are to keep this community rolling and we are now looking for a monthly venue. I have started talking to our internal HR about opening up a room (perhaps Comcast University) on a regular basis for this group. I'm looking forward to keeping the energy of this event going.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BarCampPhilly was a success!!</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcampphilly-was-a-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcampphilly-was-a-success/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.barcampphilly.org/" title="Bar Camp Philly">BarCamp&lt;/a> happened yesterday and Philly's brightest and most enthusiastic 'interative media' professionals came out in force.  Barcamp is a type of grass roots conference setup by the people bottom up rather then by a company top down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I talked a lot, learned a lot, drank a lot and made some friends in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each session exceeded my expectations in different ways.  My talk on the how we build and operate &lt;a href="http://www.comcast.net">http://www.comcast.net&lt;/a> was very well received and it was very telling to step up from the weeds and view this creation with my peers.  As much as we need to move forward sometimes we at CIM forget how far we have come.  Since this was an untelevised, ego and marketecture free event we openly discussed what we did right and wrong. Having this talk with people that live through this grind every day is very different then having it with people that learned the 'right way to build websites' from books or blogs.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Don't hire legacy developers, kill legacy systems&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>--My quote of the session&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You guys really work hard, Comcast should hire more developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>--Audience quote of the session&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>From there I went to a &amp;quot;Web Standards' talk given by someone that lived through it at AOL.  Given my challenges of getting standards adopted at Comcast this was also a great learning and sharing session. We discussed what needs to happen in our educational system and industry in order for Standards be become accepted as a core part of webdev and not a 'nice to have'.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Who would hire a web developer that does not follow standards?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>--Audience quote of the session&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>After a quick lunch attempt at a local Indian place (service in 45 min: FAIL) we returned for a talk about innovation.  My intent of this session was a he said / she said comedy routine with &lt;a href="http://arpitmathur.com/">Arpit&lt;/a> where he would play the role of the frustrated developer and I'd be more of the pointy haired boss keeping our hapless developers trudging towards a deadline.  Interesting enough this session redefined the term &amp;quot;Innovation&amp;quot; for me as the talk went in a completely different direction.  By the definition of my peers we have been innovative. Much of our innovation has not been customer facing so it does not fit with the typical management concept of what they expect to see with regard to innovation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A very interesting undercurrent was that most people innovate by padding their time or otherwise hiding this effort from their bosses.  I commented that I think this is disrespectful to the bosses and the responses again surprised me.  It turns out that most people feel that the top execs are very cluefull and 'get it' at many levels.  They also feel that the middle management just below them have no clue.  The other key factor in stifling innovation in large organizations is the inherent disrespect across disciplines. For some reason many people think that innovation has to come from their immediate team rather then the larger group.  (So for example the HTML devs have to innovate as opposed to the team consisting of HTML/IA/Design/Biz/QA etc..)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other great take home was that the entire crowd was supportive and we all wanted each other to succeed. I never experienced such a positive vibe about Comcast in Philly and how much the tech community was behind us to succeed.  There is nothing in the way of CIM (Comcast Interactive Media).  I do think that we finally have that 'critical mass' of community here in Philly and it is time that the East Coast become known as a center of innovation.  There is some great talent in this region, from us corp developers to the fierce independents at &lt;a href="http://www.indyhall.org/">Indy Hall&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;We are not the Comcast you know and hate, we are the Comcast you don't know and love&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>--Quote of the session&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>All this was less then half my day. Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phillies Parade!</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/phillies-parade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/phillies-parade/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The fountain is green: &lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/green-fountain.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/green-fountain-255x300.jpg" alt="" title="green-fountain">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Fans are lined up: &lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/img_2654.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/img_2654-300x222.jpg" alt="Philadelphia Phillies Phans" title="Parade-fans-phllies">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like a zombie hoard the fans assemble.... &lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/more-parade.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/more-parade-300x225.jpg" alt="Phillies Parade!" title="more-parade">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its coming soon!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>...and John took much better photos then I did: &lt;a href="http://flickr.com/photos/johnriv/sets/72157608543769475/">&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3294/2989125687_f90b46d713.jpg?v=1225481256" alt="John\'s Phillies Parade Photos">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accidental Obama supporter?</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/accidental-obama-supporter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/accidental-obama-supporter/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I think I just became an Obama supporter. I didn't mean to but I was pressured into it by the propaganda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've actually been on the fence until the Palin decision. (I have daughters and have a strong opinion about the difference between family values and statutory rape)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway I got an email that was anti-Obama in silly ways. I could name a number of things about him that truly concern me. I'm not sold that he would make a good president. Unfortunately our election is not about if he will be a good president, it is about if he will be better or worse the McCain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first 'fact' in this message was to cast aspersions regarding the reason that he changed his name from &amp;quot;Barry&amp;quot; to Barack. I did 5 minutes of googling to learn that his formal name is Barack and he took the nickname Barry. To attack him for that got to me in a personal way because although my given name is Aaron my dad gave me a middle name of Daniel. My middle name was just in case I had to work in an anti-semetic environment. I grew up with the need to hide my identity and culture being a very real possibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I replied to the email with this:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>His given name is Barack. Barry was a nickname in high school. As Jews we should understand the social pressure that causes someone to change their name or go my a nickname. My Hebrew name is Chaim but my dad gave me a middle name of Daniel in case I had to deal with anti-semitism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source: &lt;a href="http://www.newsweek.com/id/128633">http://www.newsweek.com/id/128633&lt;/a> (source for the Barack info, see my dad about my name)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I answered a number of things that I thought were incorrect and sent back the email. Most of the replies I got were positive but I got some more challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one made me think:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Any fact check about this story? &lt;a href="http://elections.foxnews.com/2008/10/29/mccain-slams-la-times-double-standard-withholding-obama-khalidi-tape/">http://elections.foxnews.com/2008/10/29/mccain-slams-la-times-double-standard-withholding-obama-khalidi-tape/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this &lt;a href="http://uk.news.yahoo.com/19/20081028/img/pwl-mideast-israel-palestin-f382be870d87.html">http://uk.news.yahoo.com/19/20081028/img/pwl-mideast-israel-palestin-f382be870d87.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That took me as more of a challenge so a little googling and I was able to answer them. The first was easy. Basically Barack toasted a Palestinian professor at a event ( he maybe a terrorist supporter, maybe a moderate depending on the ratio of Fox/BBC in your world view). I simply wrote back that there is factual evidence that Barack was at the event and may have said kinds words about the professor, but a committee that McCain runs funded Khalidi's organization in the US.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it appears that McCain who is talking small government and a strong America funded over $400k to give to a possible terrorist. Khalidi is such a threat that the world must know if Obama praised about him in public.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So again I've found both candidates lack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the second one bothered me more. It was about a Palestinian cold calling the US and getting people to vote Obama.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is how I answered that one:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Not sure how to 'fact check' this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A young man in another country wants to get Obama elected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can read good into this as the kid sees Obama as a hope to bring stability to the region, which would benefit him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or we can real evil into this and see the kid as wanting Obama in office because he thinks Obama will not back Israel or pour money into the hands of his terrorist friends like Khalidi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With regard to a 'fact check' I think this is a true Fact. Its really the interpretation that you are challenging. Personally having a kid make a political phone call, which our own political parties do, is much better then having him strap on a gun or bomb or kill people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isn't this what democracy is supposed to be about?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is much better then something like an Al-Qaeda terror strike before the election to scare people into voting McCain (like what happened in Spain a few years ago). &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2008/10/22/al-qaeda-supporters-endor">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2008/10/22/al-qaeda-supporters-endor&lt;/a>_n_136779.html So you are surmising that Palestinians support Obama and he is bad. I've offered a story about Al-Qaeda supporting McCain. Your story involves master plan to make phone calls. My story involves people planning something much worse:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;If al-Qaida carries out a big operation against American interests,&amp;quot; the message said, &amp;quot;this act will be support of McCain because it will push the Americans deliberately to vote for McCain so that he takes revenge for them against al-Qaida. Al-Qaida then will succeed in exhausting America till its last year in it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can't just throw down a headline anymore. Things are too critical now. We are now seeing nuclear weapons in the middle east. I don't think the MAD concept that kept us alive during the cold war will work with fanatics. People that chant slogans and cast another country or culture as evil and fit only for extinction will embrace MAD as a worthy sacrifice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>note: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclear_deterrence">mutually assured destruction&lt;/a>. See &lt;a href="http://www.fancast.com/movies/Wargames/247/main">wargames&lt;/a> for a more entertaining explaination&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did 10 minutes of research and was able to disprove a point. I didn't start out to support Obama. I started out to try to disable propaganda and let people make an informed decision. In reading back what I wrote I'm thinking that I just created some propaganda for the other side. There simply is no link to the truth. Where is the 'System of record' that has the facts linked to the key &amp;quot;Barack&amp;quot;? Leaving work today &lt;a href="http://www.paradox1x.org/">Karl&lt;/a> suggested that the Internet allows people to shelter themselves in the facts that they want to believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In grad school I learned to make charts that can take any numbers and prove (or disprove) any hypothesis. The new skill seems to be able to search the net and paste 'evidence' to support and attack any idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There may be no better example of this then the famous internet chart proving the cause of global warming is the worldwide decline of pirates: &lt;a href="http://www.seanbonner.com/blog/archives/001857.php">http://www.seanbonner.com/blog/archives/001857.php&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So for now I'll use my google-copy-paste prowess to support Obama, but clearly we in the business of the &amp;quot;Internet&amp;quot; must take a step back from this creation and examine the social aspects of what we have wrought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and I think it is imperative that every Philadelphia blogger mention that yes indeed - the&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="phillies-won">Phillies won!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And thus ends my deep thinking for the night as I follow tales of spontaneous parting on twitter. (Tomorrow's post will be on how 4 innings of baseball disrupt my attempts to solve the fundamental knowledge issues with out democracy)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Thanks &lt;a href="http://www.the700level.com/2008/10/comcast-center.html">Comcast for little billy&lt;/a>!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>"really dumb idea" or "I hope my mom does not read this"</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/really-dumb-idea-or-i-hope-my-mom-does-not-read-this/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/really-dumb-idea-or-i-hope-my-mom-does-not-read-this/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week I checked the weather and rode my motorcycle down to Philly with plans to ride back to Bucks County today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was raining and very windy in the city so I left a bit earlier for safety sake. It was cold but the road was not too slippery until I ventured onto 95N. As soon as I got the bike up to about 40mph I got hit with a crosswind and felt the back tire move sideways. At this point higher brain functions kicked in and I slowed for the next exit, Aramingo road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out I have no idea how to get home locally from this area. I literally wandered the neighborhoods, trying to keep 95 in sight and after about 25 damp minutes I somehow wandered onto Broad Street. &lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/IMG_2610.jpg" alt="motorcycle in the snow"> In an earlier phone call Jennifer mentioned to me that I could get home from Broad so I gave it a shot. I headed north and then saw route 1. I do know how to get home from Rt 1, and that is a non-elevated roadway with some decent wind protection so I went for it. Unfortunately I could only see signs for Rt 1 south and what I thought was Rt1 north turned out to be a Septa depot. A nice man rolled down his window and gave me some directions to Rt1 that I obviously got completely wrong because 20minutes later found me on Broad St. again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point my desire to get home and dry was in direct conflict with my desire to find a restroom but I pressed on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I saw a Harley Davidson sticker on the back of the SUV in front. There is a great stereotype about the Harley rider, and this was such a scene. A harley rider, dry in his SUV with his Harley fashion followed by the fully armored BMW rider on an unstoppable GS. At this point in my ride I was definitely thinking about getting a Harley ;). I man-up and pass this fellow as a rider in the opposing lane hits a long puddle and throws a rooster-tail wave my way and I'm buried in gallons on Broad Street's finest vintage.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.olympiamotosports.com/ast_mens/ast_mens.htm">Olympia AST Jacket and Pants&lt;/a> fully protected me from this downpour. I can't say enough about the water protection here. When I got home my pants and socks were a little damp, but overall I was dry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The gear didn't do a thing for the demoralizing effect of getting hit with a tsunami, but I appreciated being dry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But again I press on towards willow grove and the only low speed, ground-level route I know home. Finally my bladder cries foul and I pull into a Dunkin Donuts. Two more guys there greet me and another stops to tell me, &amp;quot;Dude, you are hardcore, I put my bike away last month&amp;quot;. I tried not to let him see my teeth chatter as I thanked him and drank some life giving coffee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back on the road after 1hr and 45minutes of travel and I hit merciful low speed traffic. This road was a sheet of ice and after I took this picture I had to ride on the median. (Taking the picture was by far not the dumbest part of the ride, but at this point my destiny may have been to serve as an object lesson for others) Try to notice the ice under the truck bumper in the photo - that was solid ice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally got home and was looking forward to a nice hot shower....and my power was out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Safety begins before the ride starts&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My trip&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;saddr=1701+Jfk+Blvd,+Philadelphia,+PA+19103+(Table+31)&amp;amp;daddr=E+Orleans+St+to:W+Allegheny+Ave+to:W+Roberts+Ave+to:Reading%2FWindrim+Ave+to:Windrim+Ave+to:40.137416,-75.111809+to:188+monroe+ct,+18966&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=FXCmYQIdmAWF-yGdBCXm9cjOzg%3BFao8YgIdvMyF-w%3BFYJfYgId8kaF-w%3BFWSRYgIdFPiE-w%3BFSSzYgIdACqF-w%3BFdbOYgId8FyF-w%3B%3B&amp;amp;mra=dpe&amp;amp;mrcr=0&amp;amp;mrsp=6&amp;amp;sz=12&amp;amp;via=1,2,3,4,5,6&amp;amp;sll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;sspn=0.156016,0.350876&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=AARTsJrJ1K12aeoTFEWuFbBhjw-u3zyGCw&amp;amp;ll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;spn=0.367717,0.583649&amp;amp;z=10&amp;amp;output=embed">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;saddr=1701+Jfk+Blvd,+Philadelphia,+PA+19103+(Table+31)&amp;amp;daddr=E+Orleans+St+to:W+Allegheny+Ave+to:W+Roberts+Ave+to:Reading%2FWindrim+Ave+to:Windrim+Ave+to:40.137416,-75.111809+to:188+monroe+ct,+18966&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=FXCmYQIdmAWF-yGdBCXm9cjOzg%3BFao8YgIdvMyF-w%3BFYJfYgId8kaF-w%3BFWSRYgIdFPiE-w%3BFSSzYgIdACqF-w%3BFdbOYgId8FyF-w%3B%3B&amp;amp;mra=dpe&amp;amp;mrcr=0&amp;amp;mrsp=6&amp;amp;sz=12&amp;amp;via=1,2,3,4,5,6&amp;amp;sll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;sspn=0.156016,0.350876&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;spn=0.367717,0.583649&amp;amp;z=10&amp;amp;source=embed">View Larger Map&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I just had to click this ad</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/i-just-had-to-click-this-ad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/i-just-had-to-click-this-ad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I had to click on this minimalist ad.  I had to know where it went.....&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/picture-1.png">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/picture-1.png" alt="Got suckered by this minimalist ad" title="minimalist ad">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1800 got Junk?</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/1800-got-junk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/1800-got-junk/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently purchased a 'pre-forclosure' townhouse and it was cluttered with a serious amount of stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first thought was to rent a dumpster and hire some movers to help me empty the house.  That would have cost about $6-$700.  I've been seeing the 1800 Got Junk trucks around the neighborhood so I thought I'd give them a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website was excellent with a design and IA that allowed me to quickly accomplish what I came there to do.  I setup an appointment for the next business day and got a price estimate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They price by volume and supply the labor to fill it.  I estimated about 75% of a truck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The called me about an hour before the appointment to confirm and I mentioned that I was at the property and they can come anytime.  They actually showed up about 40 minutes early and took a tour of the job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The kids that showed up were very respectful and nice as well as clearly being experienced at what they did.  Immediately they called for backup and within about 20 minutes 5 men were expertly emptying my house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They worked quite differently then the movers that I would have hired.  First of all they brought bags and collected all of the little items to speed their work (understandable since I'm not paying by the hour).  Anytime they came across something that may have been of value somone would bring it to my attention rather then just remove it.  They also cleaned and swept each room when they were complete.  Another interesting contrast was how they fit stuff into the truck to optimize the space without regard to breaking things.  Brought back memories of when I hired Allied to move.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall the job was well done and I would recommend them.  Had the selling Realtor done this before my purchase I would likely have paid an additional $10k for the place.  My cost was about 1/3 to 1/4 higher depending on alternatives, but this was definately the fastests and most stress free way to get it done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even booking the appointment was done on the couch during a commercial of &amp;quot;In Plain Sight&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the trifecta of personal projects</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/the-trifecta-of-personal-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/the-trifecta-of-personal-projects/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The joys of home ownership pressing demands at work have stifled my personal innovation time. Sometime in the last millennium I used be enjoy writing exploratory projects and releasing libraries that others may find useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last few months I've been looking for inspiration for a project that would help me explore some 'search' related ideas that have been bouncing in my head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I came across a project idea that represents the perfect personal trifecta!&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It involves a technology I'm currently interesting in learning&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It solves a real world problem that affects me (and many more like me ;) personally&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>My mom likes it&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I have the domain name, I have the technology, don't have a UI worth showing and absolutely no features work yet! But soon I will unveil this and learn if being desperate to use my mother for innovations works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man - great past the end</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/iron-man-great-past-the-end/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/iron-man-great-past-the-end/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I thoroughly enjoyed the Iron Man movie. My son wanted more of a &lt;a href="http://us.games-workshop.com/games/40K/spacemarines/default.htm">SpaceMarine&lt;/a> clunky feel to the armor, but I though they nailed exactly how I saw Iron Man from my youth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least half the theater stayed past the credit roll, I was surprised by how many people knew about the extra bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took some real willpower to sit through the endless list of names after consuming a super giant-sized soda and getting to a 2 hour movie 45min early&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Motocycles and Python turn toil into joy</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/motocycles-and-python-turn-toil-into-joy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/motocycles-and-python-turn-toil-into-joy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>So today started out great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Temperatures in the 80's, so I took the kiddies outside. I put my cellphone on the trunk of my sisters's car, put the kids on their bikes, put skates on my feet and rolled out to enjoy the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things were going well with my littlest one making turns at each end of the block. My sister pulled up and shouted some encouragement as she drove past. I waved and noticed my black cell phone on the white trunk of her car!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started to skate hard, but I couldn't leave my girl in the street. I shuffled the girls back into the house and summoned the boy to watch them and tore off after my sister. I searched all the likely routes she would have taken but could not find it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I called her and found out where she went and was determined to look again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I was pretty upset about this and feeling down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I got on my motorcycle and started looking for it. I rode a block at a time and dismounted to look. After about 15 minutes I realized it was looking pretty grim. I also realized I was out on my bike on a beautiful day, and any day you ride simply isn't that bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a similar occurrence with python the other day. I had to scrape some data out of a nasty, IE only, webapp. It was pretty ugly but I got into writing the app as a pyunit test case and using assertions to ensure I got all the data. The difficult nature of the data coming in made me appreciate just how much you can do with test cases. The scraping task was about as pleasurable as looking for my cellphone across town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But at least I got to do it in python and enjoy the ride!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Michael Clayton</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/movie-michael-clayton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/movie-michael-clayton/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I watched &lt;a href="http://www.fancast.com/movies/Michael-Clayton/30659/main">Michael Clayton&lt;/a> today&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.fancast.com/movies/Michael-Clayton/30659/main">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/1188416932882_15MichaelClayton_mif.jpg_121_87.jpg" alt="George Clooney as Michael Clayton" title="George Clooney as Michael Clayton">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A decent legal / espionage plot. Predictive enough. The lawyer is defending an international chemical company for years.  One day he goes off his anti-depressants and decides to champion the farmers being killed by the chemical additives. Drama ensues when the 'fixer' Michael Clayton is set on the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the lawyer who had the breakdown was Michael's friend, and since Mr. Clayton has a good relationship with his son, so we assume he is not wholly evil. Its a good thing we don't live in a world with people that would allow this to happen. A quick googling shows that our government recently decided to immediately &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/02/06/AR2007020600105.html">phase out a harmful pesticide (that has been in use since 1950s) by 2012&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron's improved ending: Michael takes the money at the end, leaves his stressful life behind and the movie closes with him sipping a drink on th beach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Technorati: &lt;a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/movie">movie&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Signing @ Kesher Isreal</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/tehst/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/tehst/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I attended a book signing and talk by &lt;a href="http://www.boonin.com/">Harry Boonin&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?hl=en&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;q=kesher+israel&amp;amp;near=Philadelphia,+PA&amp;amp;fb=1&amp;amp;cid=39942639,-75149153,8115982947485271748&amp;amp;li=lmd&amp;amp;ll=39.942713,-75.149145&amp;amp;spn=0.041326,0.072098&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;iwloc=A">Kesher Isreal&lt;/a> today.  He gave an interesting talk about the history of the temple and an insight into the history of the Jews in Philly.  An interesting bit was his mention of a part of the building's history where the Christian community collaborated with the Jewish community during a move and had mutual respect for each others religious paraphernalia.  I have to wonder how the different communities could understand each other without wikipedia!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Glock Day!</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/hello-world/</guid><description>
&lt;p>What better first post for my renovated, Philly style blog, then to mention &amp;quot;Glock Day&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A local range in the city &lt;a href="http://www.philadelphiaarcheryandgunclub.com/">(Philadelphia Archery and Gun Club)&lt;/a> hosted some helpful representatives from &lt;a href="http://www.glock.com/" title="Glock">Glock&lt;/a> and offered free test firing of their models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The staff was helpful and it was fun.  It reminded me of testing racing skis at &lt;a href="http://www.killington.com/winter/index.html">Killington&lt;/a>.  Except less of the fresh mountain air and more of the smell of gunpowder.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>