<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Aaron's Blog</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Aaron's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronheld.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OSX vs Ubuntu, Windows wins?</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/osx-vs-ubuntu-windows-wins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/osx-vs-ubuntu-windows-wins/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Ever since Barcamp I've been shopping for a personal laptop for general use as well as a development machine that I could use for work.  Our work issued machine is a loaded mac powerbook.  With a unix core osx has given me much of the power that I used to enjoy when I'd used linux as a primary os. However Apple is not doing wonders for free software and I felt the need to get back to my roots and move back to Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I picked up a 4lb HP &lt;a href="http://www.shopping.hp.com/webapp/shopping/computer_can_series.do?storeName=computer_store&amp;amp;category=notebooks&amp;amp;a1=Category&amp;amp;v1=Ultra-Portable&amp;amp;series_name=dm4t_series&amp;amp;jumpid=in_R329_prodexp/hhoslp/psg/notebooks/Ultra-Portable/dm4t_series">DM4&lt;/a> and dual booted to Ubuntu with not issues.  The trackpad didn't work right, but a script off someones blog made it work reasonably ok.  A quick hop into debug mode showed that the drivers returned negative x-y coordinates when you use 2 fingers.  I downloaded the open source drivers to take a look at the code and saw that a patch was already in head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Developing was a joy and eclipse opened nearly instantly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft silverlight DRM is not (yet?) ported to linux so I dual boot to windows 7 to get the customer experience and use CIM products.  A funny thing happened to me while getting the 'customer' experience.   I liked it!   Windows 7 is much more usable then either osx or Linux and IE9 looks like it will be a really powerful platform for future development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Around this time I picked up a python update on OSX and spent about 4 hours trying to get mysql and python to &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=mysql+python+osx">talk to each other&lt;/a>.  I booted into windows and thought about how to use this platform as a development machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter &lt;a href="http://bitnami.org/">BitNami&lt;/a>. Rather then deal with version conflicts I grabbed a virtual machine that is close to my target server and installed VMware Player.  Mapping a windows directory to the virtual machine lets me edit files in native windows while running my build chain on Linux.  The browser I use for development is finally the same browser used by the majority of my customers and my dev environment is much closer to my server environment as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For not I'm working through the rough edges of this setup and trying to find a decent windows SSH client but this setup seems to have legs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>