<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chucknorris on Aaron's Blog</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/categories/chucknorris/</link><description>Recent content in chucknorris on Aaron's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronheld.com/categories/chucknorris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PPA ending 65mpg &amp; free parking</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/ppa-ending-65mpg-free-parking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/ppa-ending-65mpg-free-parking/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A friendly PPA agent gave me some unpleasant news today. I was respectfully loading my bike and moving it from its unobtrusive parking spot on 20th and Market when he walked by.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've notices some motorcycle shaped parking spots on that corner and knew this news was coming. Turns out that if you charge 50% for motorcycle parking but put 4 bikes in a car slot you can still earn 2x in parking fees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you only get to make the cash if you have armies of people 'encouraging' riders not to park on the free abandoned lot or in alleys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.kyw1060.com/Philadelphia-Considers-Motorcycle-Only-Parking-Spa/5123020">http://www.kyw1060.com/Philadelphia-Considers-Motorcycle-Only-Parking-Spa/5123020&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ride for the pleasure of it as well as for the economy. I pay as much to park my car at the septa station as I do in fuel for the entire ride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As much as I enjoy riding if I have to pay for a day of off-street parking anyway I may as well drive the car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With winter coming I guess the PPA is doing its share. If we all abandon 2 wheels for 4 we will warm the globe and slash heating costs this winter....&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a bike makes Philly an even better town then it already is. I can easily zip from work in center city to dinner in chinatown and then cruise home. There must a better way to preserve Philly's growing reputation as a scooter friendly city....&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HOA - Case study of failed political systems</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/hoa-failed-political-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/hoa-failed-political-systems/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I love to rant over how bad HOAs are.  There are so many case studies in my life where otherwise happy friendly people become tyrants when given a bit of power.  From the band leader that threatened my wedding would be a failure to the people that run the Home Owners Associations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes a certain type of fellow to run an HOA.  My buck's county HOA is much better then the one in Manalanapan.  They forced me to keep human feces in my garage, (more about dirty diapers and not allowing a gargage can to be on the side of the house) and would not let a neighbor keep a boat in the lot because it was not a car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have not been in my current place long enough to have any issues but I think the culture and spirit of the HOA is well captured by this web form that they host.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_201&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Do you see the 'post' button?&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/picture-4.png">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/picture-4-300x119.png" alt="Do you see the 'post' button?" title="HOA forum">&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google's iterative design for search</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/googles-iterative-design-for-search/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/googles-iterative-design-for-search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The google blog recently put up a remarkably content-free post on their product blog about how they use iterative design and usability studies to develop enhancements to their core search offering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2009/05/behind-scenes-of-search-options-panel.html">Official Google Blog: Behind the scenes of the Search Options panel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do similar testing for our search product (&lt;a href="http://search.comcast.net">http://search.comcast.net&lt;/a>) and we actually run 8-12 live tests at any given time.  The real users using the product in the wild give us fantastic insight that is combined with the more traditional studies in order to guide us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm embarking on a similar approach for our new CMS initiative and I'm still on iteration 0.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don't have pretty design concepts to show yet, but I do have cartoon wall art!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_196&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;sketch of page designer&amp;quot;]&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/build-a-page-sketch1.jpg" alt="sketch of page designer" title="build-a-page-sketch1">[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insta-Tag Cloud</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/insta-tag-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/insta-tag-cloud/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Cute tag-cloud generator off my feed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;img src="http://www.wordle.net/thumb/wrdl/875557/Aaron%27s_Blog" alt="Wordle: Aaron's Blog">](&lt;a href="http://www.wordle.net/gallery/wrdl/875557/Aaron%27s_Blog">http://www.wordle.net/gallery/wrdl/875557/Aaron%27s_Blog&lt;/a> &amp;quot;&amp;quot;Wordle: Aaron's Blog&amp;quot;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper prototyping success!</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/paper-prototyping-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/paper-prototyping-success/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Over in CIM we are working on a major CMS overhaul based on Alfresco. Alfresco gives me the solid foundation of what I need in terms of content APIs, scalability and workflow. Unfortunately the UI leaves something to be desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've decided to focus my teams efforts on the Editorial interface of the CMS and really want to get it right. CMS projects in general are prone to dissatisfaction and most people using 'enterprise' CMSs don't really like them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to give us the best chance of success we have a dedicated team working collaboratively from the outset.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I locked the team in a room today and presented them with one question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do users FIND content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finding content is a critical part of any tool and something that our current CMS does pretty well. It was really interesting to listen to the widely different perspectives. Some of the editors wanted more of a 'structured' tree based navigation while the more business users were looking to a search. Ops like a faceted search.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interestingly the operations folk didn't think that they could contribute originally but part of the concept behind this exercise was team building so I encouraged them to stay. I asked them how do they locate a specific hard drive in all the servers in all the racks in the 5 data centers that they manage? How do they locate a specific Zone file in the hundred's of DNS records they maintain? Turns out our operational folk know a bit about using a UI to locate things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By getting everyone involved we did weeks worth of 'requirements gathering' and documentation in half a day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Full credit to &lt;a href="http://toddwarfel.com/">Todd Warfel&lt;/a> for the &lt;a href="http://refreshPhilly.org">RefreshPhilly&lt;/a> talk that opened my eyes to the simplicity and power of this direct approach&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smartzone shortcuts</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/smartzone-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/smartzone-shortcuts/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I'm starting to get used to Comcast's &lt;a href="http://www.comcast.net/smartzone/" title="Smartzone">smartzone webmail front end&lt;/a>.  It is an ajaxy / desktopish mail client that exposes way more functionality then the old one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This type of functionality usually comes at a price, and in this case the price was having to use a mouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of keyboard shortcuts, but the it is a full page help buried in the preferences pane.  I prefer the narrow right-hand window like the type seen in some Microsoft office products.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I copied the docs and make a little bookmarklet for myself.  Feel free to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Smartzone Keyboard Shortcuts](javascript:(function(){var width = 350;var top = 150;var height=screen.height - top;var left =screen.width - width;var winpop=open( 'http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/shortcuts.html', 'win', 'scrollbars=yes,resizeable=no,menubar=no,toolbar=no,width='+width+',height='+height+',left='+left+',top='+top);})() &amp;quot;Shortcuts&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use this as a bookmarklet, just drag it over to your bookmark or favorites bar!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ardith learns about reducing scope</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/ardit-learning-about-reducing-scope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/ardit-learning-about-reducing-scope/</guid><description>
&lt;p>So tonight my 10 year old decided that she wanted to learn flash. We are going through a basic tutorial but she decided to make a cat (rather then a circle) walk across the screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is clearly scope creep! There was budgeted time after dinner and before bed for a circle slide, not a walking mammal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some time she said that it didn't look right and wanted to spend more time in order to make it walk more realistically. I said that it was bedtime. Like any good developer faced with their project time getting cut she looked to reduce scope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ardith puts little circles under its feed, compiles and says,&amp;quot;Look - roller skates!&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The requirement of a cat moving across screen has been satisfied.....&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[kml_flashembed fversion=&amp;quot;8.0.0&amp;quot; movie=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/ardith-cat.swf&amp;quot; targetclass=&amp;quot;flashmovie&amp;quot; publishmethod=&amp;quot;static&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://adobe.com/go/getflashplayer">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/get_flash_player.gif" alt="Get Adobe Flash player">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[/kml_flashembed]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>first 'real' refreshPhilly event</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/first-real-refreshphilly-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/first-real-refreshphilly-event/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The first round of 'official' speakers set the bar pretty high for refreshPhilly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tom Boutell from &lt;a href="http://www.punkave.com/">www.punkave.com&lt;/a> gave us a talk on symphony and set the tone of the crowd as a hardcore web devs followed by Phil Charron and Russ Starke who brilliently challenged us to the core.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dragging up memories of aquaman they threw down the simple question:  So what exactly &lt;em>are&lt;/em> we going to do for Philly?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>virus alert!</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/virus-alert/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/virus-alert/</guid><description>
&lt;p>While hunting online for that movie with the couple who pay thier neighbors to act normal so they can sell thier home I got redirected to this nicely done virus page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its a convincing experience to get the user to download and install the application.  I wonder if these criminals would be open to oursourcing some IA work that I need done?????&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_114&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Well done social engineerig page to install a virus&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/virus.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/virus-300x187.jpg" alt="Well done social engineerig page to install a virus" title="virus">&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>missing my mac</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/missing-my-mac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/missing-my-mac/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My sleek mac is more like a Jaguar then a chevy.  Yes it is in the shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My machine and 4 of its cousins left our office last week for an undisclosed service center for an indeterminate amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm using a Dell laptop.  The dell hardware is really solid as is the wireless connectivity.  The operating system is windows on top of full drive encryption so the software experience leaves something to be desired.  When I unplug the wire it immediately hops onto the corporate wireless network, something the mac can't do (yet).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My next exploration will be to figure out how to script osx such that when the ethernet is unplugged it looks for the hidden SSID of the corp wireless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the meantime I did get a laugh out of an NCIS rerun where &lt;a href="http://cbsncis.wetpaint.com/page/Ziva+David">Ziva&lt;/a> plays whack-a-mole with error dialogs on her Windows PC and says,&amp;quot; At Massad we used Mac&amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BarCamp or Mac ad?</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcamp-or-mac-ad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/barcamp-or-mac-ad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Sorting through Barcamp photos. Is this a session or mac ad? Macbooks and iphones everywhere. I'd love to know the percentages.[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_66&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;450&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Mac ad or conference session&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/mac-ad-pbc.jpg">&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/mac-ad-pbc.jpg" alt="Mac ad or conference session" title="mac-ad-pbc">&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>best election video so far</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/best-election-video-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/best-election-video-so-far/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The combination of cutting edge on-demand video creation and old school guilt!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch it &lt;a href="http://www.cnnbcvideo.com/?combined=Aaron%20Held&amp;amp;first=Aaron&amp;amp;name_id=9406856&amp;amp;last=Held&amp;amp;id=-13807711-QWQp3rx&amp;amp;nid=PlqECJgn8MZulM9kXVhqvDk0MDY4NTY-">here&lt;br>
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_38&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;election guilt for Aaron Held&amp;quot;]&lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/assets/posts/images/picture-2-300x209.png" alt="election guilt for Aaron Held" title="election guilt">[/caption]&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>public takes action to stop a police beating</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/public-takes-action-to-stop-a-police-beating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/public-takes-action-to-stop-a-police-beating/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I came across this video on a soccer/fan site and would love to know the context. My multilingual friends are encouraged to reply....&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>"really dumb idea" or "I hope my mom does not read this"</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/really-dumb-idea-or-i-hope-my-mom-does-not-read-this/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/really-dumb-idea-or-i-hope-my-mom-does-not-read-this/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week I checked the weather and rode my motorcycle down to Philly with plans to ride back to Bucks County today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was raining and very windy in the city so I left a bit earlier for safety sake. It was cold but the road was not too slippery until I ventured onto 95N. As soon as I got the bike up to about 40mph I got hit with a crosswind and felt the back tire move sideways. At this point higher brain functions kicked in and I slowed for the next exit, Aramingo road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out I have no idea how to get home locally from this area. I literally wandered the neighborhoods, trying to keep 95 in sight and after about 25 damp minutes I somehow wandered onto Broad Street. &lt;img src="https://www.aaronheld.com/wp-content/IMG_2610.jpg" alt="motorcycle in the snow"> In an earlier phone call Jennifer mentioned to me that I could get home from Broad so I gave it a shot. I headed north and then saw route 1. I do know how to get home from Rt 1, and that is a non-elevated roadway with some decent wind protection so I went for it. Unfortunately I could only see signs for Rt 1 south and what I thought was Rt1 north turned out to be a Septa depot. A nice man rolled down his window and gave me some directions to Rt1 that I obviously got completely wrong because 20minutes later found me on Broad St. again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point my desire to get home and dry was in direct conflict with my desire to find a restroom but I pressed on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I saw a Harley Davidson sticker on the back of the SUV in front. There is a great stereotype about the Harley rider, and this was such a scene. A harley rider, dry in his SUV with his Harley fashion followed by the fully armored BMW rider on an unstoppable GS. At this point in my ride I was definitely thinking about getting a Harley ;). I man-up and pass this fellow as a rider in the opposing lane hits a long puddle and throws a rooster-tail wave my way and I'm buried in gallons on Broad Street's finest vintage.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.olympiamotosports.com/ast_mens/ast_mens.htm">Olympia AST Jacket and Pants&lt;/a> fully protected me from this downpour. I can't say enough about the water protection here. When I got home my pants and socks were a little damp, but overall I was dry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The gear didn't do a thing for the demoralizing effect of getting hit with a tsunami, but I appreciated being dry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But again I press on towards willow grove and the only low speed, ground-level route I know home. Finally my bladder cries foul and I pull into a Dunkin Donuts. Two more guys there greet me and another stops to tell me, &amp;quot;Dude, you are hardcore, I put my bike away last month&amp;quot;. I tried not to let him see my teeth chatter as I thanked him and drank some life giving coffee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back on the road after 1hr and 45minutes of travel and I hit merciful low speed traffic. This road was a sheet of ice and after I took this picture I had to ride on the median. (Taking the picture was by far not the dumbest part of the ride, but at this point my destiny may have been to serve as an object lesson for others) Try to notice the ice under the truck bumper in the photo - that was solid ice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally got home and was looking forward to a nice hot shower....and my power was out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Safety begins before the ride starts&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My trip&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;saddr=1701+Jfk+Blvd,+Philadelphia,+PA+19103+(Table+31)&amp;amp;daddr=E+Orleans+St+to:W+Allegheny+Ave+to:W+Roberts+Ave+to:Reading%2FWindrim+Ave+to:Windrim+Ave+to:40.137416,-75.111809+to:188+monroe+ct,+18966&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=FXCmYQIdmAWF-yGdBCXm9cjOzg%3BFao8YgIdvMyF-w%3BFYJfYgId8kaF-w%3BFWSRYgIdFPiE-w%3BFSSzYgIdACqF-w%3BFdbOYgId8FyF-w%3B%3B&amp;amp;mra=dpe&amp;amp;mrcr=0&amp;amp;mrsp=6&amp;amp;sz=12&amp;amp;via=1,2,3,4,5,6&amp;amp;sll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;sspn=0.156016,0.350876&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=AARTsJrJ1K12aeoTFEWuFbBhjw-u3zyGCw&amp;amp;ll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;spn=0.367717,0.583649&amp;amp;z=10&amp;amp;output=embed">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;saddr=1701+Jfk+Blvd,+Philadelphia,+PA+19103+(Table+31)&amp;amp;daddr=E+Orleans+St+to:W+Allegheny+Ave+to:W+Roberts+Ave+to:Reading%2FWindrim+Ave+to:Windrim+Ave+to:40.137416,-75.111809+to:188+monroe+ct,+18966&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=FXCmYQIdmAWF-yGdBCXm9cjOzg%3BFao8YgIdvMyF-w%3BFYJfYgId8kaF-w%3BFWSRYgIdFPiE-w%3BFSSzYgIdACqF-w%3BFdbOYgId8FyF-w%3B%3B&amp;amp;mra=dpe&amp;amp;mrcr=0&amp;amp;mrsp=6&amp;amp;sz=12&amp;amp;via=1,2,3,4,5,6&amp;amp;sll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;sspn=0.156016,0.350876&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=40.089892,-75.071297&amp;amp;spn=0.367717,0.583649&amp;amp;z=10&amp;amp;source=embed">View Larger Map&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>