<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>process on Aaron's Blog</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/tags/process/</link><description>Recent content in process on Aaron's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronheld.com/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project Management is critical for Useless projects</title><link>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/project-management-is-critical-for-useless-projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aaronheld.com/post/project-management-is-critical-for-useless-projects/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This about this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a project with an estimated cost of $1MM and you expect a return of $1.1MM then strict governance and process controls are critical to success. A variance of 10% will take you from profitability to a loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a project with the same estimated $1MM cost but an expected return of $50MM then project management is less critical. a 10% variance will not really matter in the big picture. Given my fictional example even a 100% to 500% cost overrun could happen and keep the &amp;quot;success&amp;quot; label.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the take home message is that project management is critical for useless projects. If you have a great project then even with terrible project management you will still be successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my own experience we run a might tighter governance on the weekly 'Features and Maintenance' sprint team as opposed to the month long 'bigger feature' sprint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So put your bad PMs on key initiatives and shuffle the best to the menial tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And get yourself on a 'no-fail' path by ensuring that all your projects have large ROI with logarithmic (hockey stick) growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love reading articles by fearless people with 'tenure' at IEEE!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www2.computer.org/portal/web/computingnow/0709/whatsnew/software-r">http://www2.computer.org/portal/web/computingnow/0709/whatsnew/software-r&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>